Guide to the Teamsters for a Democratic Union, New York - New Jersey Chapter Records WAG.136
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Teamsters for a Democratic Union, New York - New Jersey Chapter Records
1961-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Teamsters for a Democratic Union. New York - New Jersey Chapter
WAG.136
10.5 Linear Feet in 10 record cartons and 1 manuscript box.
Teamsters for a Democratic Union was formed in the 1970s by rank-and-file members of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters to combat corruption in their union. The New York - New Jersey regional office of the TDU was established in 1987. Materials include administrative records of the TDU, materials related to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, records pertaining to Teamsters locals, records related to divisions within the union, individual grievances, legal records, correspondence, resource materials, and photographs.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into seven series:
The records are organized into nine series:
Missing Title
Series I: Organizational Records, 1965-1994
Series II: International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1968-1994
Series III: International Brotherhood of Teamsters Locals, 1961-1994
Series IV: Divisions, 1975-1998
Series V: Grievants (Individuals), 1984-1989
Series VI: Legal, 1977-1994
Series VII: Resource Materials, 1977-1995
Series VIII: Unprocessed Material
Series IX: Photographs
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Association for Union Democracy: NY Area Files (WAG 302)
Burton Hall Papers (WAG 087)
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 138 Records (WAG 153)
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 282, FORE (Fear of Reprisal Ends) Records (WAG 107)
Gary Stevenson Papers (WAG 182)
"Rank-and-file Teamster Movements in Comparative Perspective," by Aaron Brenner. Trade Union Politics: American Unions and Economic Change 1960s - 1990s. Edited by Glenn Perusek and Kent Worcester. New Jersey: Humanities Press, 1995.
"Where is the Teamster Rebellion Going?" by Staughton Lynd. Workers' Struggles, Past and Present: A Radical America Reader. Edited by James Green. Philadelphia: Temple University Press, 1983.
Teamster Rank and File Legal Rights Handbook. Detroit: TDU 1979; 1984
TDU: 10 Years and Going Strong. Detroit; TDU, 1985.
Brenner, Aaron. Rank-and-File Rebellion: 1966-1975. Thesis: Columbia University, 1996.
Crowe, Kenneth C. Collision: How the Rank and File Took Back the Teamsters. New York: Scribner's, 1993.
Friedman, Samuel L. Teamster Rank and File: Power, Bureaucracy, and Rebellion at Work and in a Union. New York: Columbia University Press, 1982.
La Botz, Dan. Rank and File Rebellion: TDU. New York: Verso, 1990.
Jacobs, James B. Busting the Mob: U.S. v. Cosa Nostra. New York: New York University Press, 1994.
Zeller, Duke. Devil's Pact: Inside the World of the Teamsters Union. Secaucus: Carol Publishing, 1996.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Teamsters for a Democratic Union, New York - New Jersey Chapter in 1998 and 2003. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2003.021 and 2003.022.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York metropolitan region has one of the largest concentrations of Teamster members and local unions in the U.S. Over 100,000 Teamsters work in a huge range of industries in New York and New Jersey. New York has played an important part in the history of the International union.
In 1970 in New York City, a committed band of activists in Local 282 organized a dissident group, FORE - Fear of Reprisal Ends. They issued a newsletter, bulletins, ran election campaigns in their local, issued challenges to their corrupt leadership through the National Labor Relations Board and through the courts. They organized by addressing issues related to contracts, grievances, pension fund loans, etc. While a tiny minority within their 4,500 member local, they kept up the pressure on their union officials, many of whom eventually went to jail.
In 1975, the Teamsters for a Democratic Contract (TDC) was formed to pressure IBT President Frank Fitzsimmons into supporting certain demands in upcoming negotiations. Following an attack on a TDC member attending the 1976 national Teamster convention, an enlarged TDC became the Teamsters for a Democratic Union (TDU). The Convoy Dispatch, TDC's national newspaper, continued its existence as the paper for the TDU. The reform group developed its greatest strength in the core jurisdictions of the IBT - freight trucking; carhauling; grocery delivery and United Parcel Service (UPS). In 1987-1988, TDU was able to organize three straight contract rejections - the UPS contract, the National Master Freight Agreement (NMFA), and the Carhaul (national) contract. The 80s posed a difficult set of problems for the reform group. With the balance of power shifting to the employers side due to de-regulation and a severe economic recession, it became more difficult to pull off militant actions. Local organizing efforts concentrated on basic educational, contractual, grievance, by-law reform campaigns and electoral activities.
In 1991, Ron Carey, head of New York's Local 804, endorsed by TDU a full two years before the election, was elected as general president of the union in December 1991, winning 16 of the 17 spots on the IBT international executive board. Seven of Carey's 16-member slate were members of TDU.
In 1996, with Carey running for a second term, the head of New York's Joint Council 16, Anthony Rumore, officially stayed on the sidelines. Rumore, as president of the 130,000-member Council, was the most powerful Teamster in the East. "The so-called wiseguys got better contracts for the people than all the new white horses," he said. But the "white horses," despite turning out more than 200 reputed mobsters, and shaking up the union structurally and programmatically, were themselves turned out of office by government charges. The epic and systematic problems associated with the NY-NJ Teamsters continue. The New York-New Jersey metropolitan area poses particular problems. For the most part, teamsters are working in marginal industries and/or companies that have long suffered under substandard Teamster contracts. Minorities form an increasingly large proportion of the membership. As David Pratt, staff organizer for the NY-NJ Chapter writes: "the fragmented, structural arrangement makes it extremely difficult for members to pool their resources and make changes in their locals. The battle for democracy is fought shop by shop and local by tiny local."
Sources
"Rank-and-file Teamster Movements in Comparative Perspective," by Aaron Brenner. Trade Union Politics: American Unions and Economic Change 1960s - 1990s. Edited by Glenn Perusek and Kent Worcester. New Jersey: Humanities Press, 1995.
"Where is the Teamster Rebellion Going?" by Staughton Lynd. Workers' Struggles, Past and Present: A Radical America Reader. Edited by James Green. Philadelphia: Temple University Press, 1983.
Teamster Rank and File Legal Rights Handbook. Detroit: TDU 1979; 1984
TDU: 10 Years and Going Strong. Detroit; TDU, 1985.
Brenner, Aaron. "Rank-and-File Rebellion: 1966-1975. PhD Dissertation: Columbia University, 1996.
Crowe, Kenneth C. Collision: How the Rank and File Took Back the Teamsters. New York: Scribner's, 1993.
Friedman, Samuel L. Teamster Rank and File: Power, Bureaucracy, and Rebellion at Work and in a Union. New York: Columbia University Press, 1982.
La Botz, Dan. Rank and File Rebellion: TDU. New York: Verso, 1990.
Jacobs, James B. Busting the Mob: U.S. v. Cosa Nostra. New York: New York University Press, 1994.
Zeller, Duke. Devil's Pact: Inside the World of the Teamsters Union. Secaucus: Carol Publishing, 1996.
Scope and Contents
The Teamsters for a Democratic Union, New York - New Jersey Chapter Records includes administrative records of the TDU, materials related to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, records pertaining to Teamsters locals, records related to divisions within the union, individual grievances, legal records, correspondence, resource materials, and photographs.
Organized crime |z New York (State); Labor contract.; Bylaws (administrative records).; Labor unions -- Political activity -- United States.; Correspondence.; Labor union democracy -- New York (State) -- New York.; Labor unions -- Corrupt practices -- New York (State); Photographs.; Labor unions -- Organizing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Labor unions |z New Jersey.; Legal documents.; International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Local 138; International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Local 282. FORE (Fear of Reprisal Ends).; International Brotherhood of Teamsters; Teamsters for a Democratic Union; Teamsters for a Democratic Union. New York - New Jersey Chapter; Jennick, Susan; Teamsters for a Democratic Union. New York - New Jersey Chapter
- Series I: Organizational Records, 1965-1994
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I includes TDU materials, including convention materials, steering committee notes, agendas, financial reports and organizing materials, rank and file flyers and campaign materials.
  - TDU Convention, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - International Steering Committee; Minutes, Agenda Proposals, TRF Reports; Printed Material re: Convention, 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - International Steering Committee; Correspondence, 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International Steering Committee Mailings, 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NY-NJ-Steering Committee, Secretary-Treasurers's Reports, Notes, Membership Lists, Correspondence, 1985, 1986, 1992, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - TDU Organizers Manual, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Organizing Workshop: Leadership, Steward's Training: Test Cases, Questionnaire, Exercises, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Organizing Workshop: A Course For Stewards and Rank and File, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Organizing Workshop: Evaluations, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Organizing Workshop: Correspondence; Press; Notes of Sue Jennik, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting Procedures / Officer, Chapter Evaluations, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Rank and File Press, Flyers, 1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - TDU Flyers and Related Press; Materials Order Form, 1988, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NMFA "Fighting for our Future", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial Records; Reports, 1988, 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Financial Reports, 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - TDU Travel Vouchers/ Petty Expenditures, 1988, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Teamster Rank and File Ed. and Legal Defense, Veatch Program: Correspondence, Grant Applications, Project Abstract, 1977-1980, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Programs, TDU and IBT Conventions, 1981, 1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Legal, Organizing, TDU (Detroit, NY), 1985-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Department of Labor Suit- TDU/ AUD (Correspondence) IBT Elections, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Department of Labor Suit- TDU and AUD (Correspondence)- IBT Elections, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Right to Vote Campaign; Petitions, Newsletter, Publicity, Press, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Reactions to Trusteeship /RICO Suit (TDU;AUD; Legal Correspondence), 1986, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - IBT Locals, Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - New York State Organized Crime Task Force - Correspondence - Construction, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - NLRB/ Court-Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - No. California Organizing- Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Women in the Membership- Correspondence; List; Discrimination, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Notes of Susan Jennik; Ken Paff; Steve Kindred, 1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Contact Proposals; Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notes of Dan Bender (Correspondence; K. Paff - Carhauler), 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Resume of Susan Jennik, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - New York-New Jersey Logo, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - TDU Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Membership Lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - TDU Membership; Mailing Lists (Carhaulers), 1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Lists; Employers, Mailing Lists, Sign-Ins, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Series II: International Brotherhood of Teamsters Materials, 1968-1994
  Series II consists of IBT materials collected by TDU. This includes material on the International's by-laws and constitution; convention materials; contracts and supplemental agreements; pension materials; various government records required by the LMRDA and material published under the Ron Carey administration on women in the union.
  - Constitutions and By-Laws, 1988, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Convention Materials, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Regional, Local, Company Contracts and Agreements, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Southern Conference Area Local Freight Supplemental Agreement Guide, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Regional, Local, Company Contracts and Agreements, 1986-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Collective Bargaining Agreements and Changes, 1985, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - UPS Pension Plan, Summary of Nat'l Master Agreement; Memorandum of Agreement, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Pension Materials (Locals 202, 1518), 1968, 1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - LM-2's, Local Unions 138, 177, 295, 338, 355, 478, 701, 867, 875, 887, 918, 999, 1034, 1205, 1518; 990's; LU's 72, 832, 858, R&F Educ.; Benefit Fund; LM-2s; Joint. Councils 16, 73, 17, 18, 64 (+Tax returns), 1982-1994 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Manual-Women in the Union (Carey Adm.), undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series III: International Brotherhood of Teamsters Locals, 1961-1994
  Series III is arranged by Local numbers; the material relate to specific campaigns undertaken in those locals. Some records relate to pension fund campaigns and the efforts of TDU staff, in particular Susan Jennik to secure pension benefits for members. Additional materials include election records, mediation and arbitration awards; NLRB cases and grievance files; and collective bargaining. The records of Local 560, with its history of corruption and lengthy government-imposed trusteeship are of particular interest.
  - Local 11 (NJ) Correspondence, Notes; Nestle Foods (Grievance), 1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Local 177 (NJ) Correspondence, Membership Lists, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Local 469 (NJ) Marino, Peirano Grievances; Correspondence, Medical Records, Notes of Susan Jennik; " Dear Abby's, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Local 641 (NJ); Discharge of M. Monroe; NJ v. Del Monte; Complaint of Lonnie Bedel; Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Local 680 (NJ) Dale Orendach Case; Correspondence, Complaint Forms, Notes of Susan Jennik; Related Press, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Local 701(NJ) Matuzak Pension Case, Van Arsdale; Treadway, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Local 1518 (NJ) Constitution and By-laws, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - No. New Jersey Pension Fund Cases, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - No. New Jersey Pension Fund Cases, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Upstate N.Y. Correspondence; Joseph Ditta - Buffalo, 1984,1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Upstate N.Y. In-House Correspondence, 1985, 1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Upstate N.Y. R & F Correspondence; Lists; Flyers; Press, 1985-1988, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Local 27 (NY) Shangold Complaint, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Local 138 (NY) forms #5500 (Actuarial), Local 138 Pension Trust Fund, Annual Financial Report (1983) and Relevant Correspondence, 1976-1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Local 138 (NY) Forms 5500 (Actuarial), 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Local 138 (NY) Key Food; Grievances, Correspondence; Notes of Susan Jennik; R&F Media; Employee List; R&F Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Local 138 (NY) Reform Slate (Correspondence), 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Local 138 (NY) Agreements with Greater NY Wholesalers Association Pension and Trust Fund Synopsis; Constitution and By-laws; White Rose; Key Foods, 1961, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Local 138 (NY) Modern Maid Food, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Local 138 (NY) White Rose/Key Food; Lauer v. LU 13 & IBT LU 138 v. White Rose; Correspondence, 1985-1986, 1990; undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Local 182 (NY) Kelley v. Harron Communications Grievance, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Local 182 (NY) Correspondence; Election Protests, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Local 202 (NY); Keller Pension Case; Correspondence; Notes of Sue Jennik; Sanchez and Rodriquez v.Sanchez and Rodriques v. Goodie Brand, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Local 237 (NY) NYC Housing Authority Agreement, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Local 272 (NY) Agreement Schedules, Employer Lists Flyers, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Local 282 (NY) Pension Fund Case, 1985, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Local 282 (NY) Katsaros, Kuebler, Kudla, Van Romer et al. v. Willets Pt. Const. Corp., NLRB, LU 282 IBT, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Local 282 (NY) Katsaros, Kuebler, Curd et al.; Correspondence; Notes, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Local 294 (NY) Correspondence; Notes of Susan Jennik; Press, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Local 338 (NY) Harry Keller- Dellwood Foods, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Local 449 (NY) Chadwick Grievance: Murello Grievance; Agreement between Cryogenic Carriers + LU 449, 1977-1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Local 456 (NY) Lucille Lock Grievance; Grievance; Correspondence; Notes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Local 553 (NY) Correspondence; LM-2's: Contracts & Agreements, Membership and Attendance Lists, 1979-1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - U.S. v. Local 560 (NJ) (CIV-86-0689); Notices of Motion to Participate as Amicus Curiae; Correspondence; Opinion and Order; NJ. State BD. of Mediation; ABF Freight Systems, INC v. Local 560 IBT; Opinion and Reward, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Local 560 (NJ); Correspondence; Surveillance Transcripts; 1983 LM-2; Notes; Flyers, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Local 584 (NJ); Election; Milk Strike Clippings; Notes, 1978, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Local 804 (NJ); Correspondence, Notes; Election Material; Tannenbaum, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Local 804 (NJ); Litigation; Grievances; Arbitrations, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - North East Region (Correspondence; Flyers), 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Local 42 (MA); Buotte v. UPS: Doty v. LU 42; Related Press; Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Local 560 (MA); Papers of Row Easton; Grievances; Nat'l, North East Agreements; Memoranda to...; Notes of Susan Jennik, 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Local 404 (MA); Frank DeGeorge Benefits Case; Synopsis, Correspondence; Susan Jennik's Notes, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - TDU-N.H; Correspondence; Classification Agreements; State ADM Rules, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Local 251 (RI); Correspondence; Caterio et al. v. J, Leo Barry (IBT); Notes, 1986, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Local 251 (RI); TNT-Redstar Exp. V Arthur Snow Cases 1-CA-25, 604; 1-CA-25, 678, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Local 654 (OH) Dallas and Mavis Forwarding Co. v. IBT, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Local 470 (PA); Preston Trucking Case; Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Southern Conference; J. David Floyd v. Auto Convoy-Arbitration, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Western Conference/LU's 104; 299: Correspondence, 1984-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Divisions, 1975-1988
  The materials in Series IV are divided as follows: Carhaul, Freight, and the National Master Freight Agreement. These records include materials from companies such as Roadway and Consolidated Freightways, two examples of national freight companies strengthened and emboldened by de-regulation.
  - Carhaul; Legal Correspondence; Stipulation of Agreement; Summary; Related Legal Texts; Related Press, 1979-1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carhaul; Related Grievances, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Carhaul; Grievances; Correspondence; Flyers; Proposals; Notes, 1984, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carhaul Rates, 1983, 1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Company Propaganda; Counter Proposals; Correspondence; Press - Carhaul Strike, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Carhaul et al. v. Jackie Presser and IBT CARhaul Election Ballots, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Carhaul; Rank and File Press, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - NMFA Contract Meeting Reports, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - NMFA Correspondence; Notes; (Jennik; Paff), 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NMFA Related Press, R&F Press, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - S.T.R.I.V.E Lists of Donors; Petition (NMFA) to Support Voting Equality, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - National Master Automobile Transporters Agreement, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Anchor-NUCAR - Leaseway Grievances (Barbara Harvey, Esq.Correspondence), 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Auto-Convoy, Anchor Freight; Correspondence of Barbara Harvey, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Auto-Handing; Grievances, Repair Reports, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Charles of the Ritz and IBT Local 1518 (NJ); Arbitration, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Consolidated Freightways (I.C.C), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Jones Motor Co. Inc. Agreement and Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Jones Motor Co. Inc. Drivers Logs, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Leaseway Employee Buyout; Explanations of ..., Draft of Articles of Association; Newsletter, Notes, Relevant Press, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Ryder System; Report To Special Committee; Tables; Pre-Arbitration Recommendations from Union; Financial Profile; FICA, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Series V: Grievants (Individuals), 1984-1989
  Series V contains files on grievances of the trucking-industry employees.
  - Ernie Aragon (LU 492) v. ABF Freight System, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Joe Barroqueiro v. Preston Trucking Co. (1 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Joe Barroqueiro v. Preston Trucking Co. (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Richard Beikert v. Key Food, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Hufstetler v. Roadway Express; Final Decision and Order, August 21, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Stephen H. Kelly v. Joseph Cory Delivery Service, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Long v. Roadway Express; Finding; Order; Legal Text, June 29, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pizzuto v. Paul's Trucking Co.; Correspondence, Affidavits, Notes, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Johnny Platt Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Walter Stack v. Preston Trucking; Recommended Decision and Order, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Roger Thomas v. Cooper Trucking, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - E. J. White v. Anchor Motor Freight; Opinion; Appellants Brief, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Legal, 1977-1994
  Series VI is organized by court cases, many involving pension and benefit funds. The records also include materials from the government's case against the international union, U.S. v. La Cosa Nostra. Individuals featured include Dellacroce and Salerno. Some material relates to Jackie Presser's role as a government informant (see "Identity of Informant known as "Alpro.") The records contain the settlement and documents pertaining to supervision of the first direct election in the union's history. Materials developed by the TDU in preparation for the election are included in this series.
  - Legal Opinion and Order: Right to Vote on Wage Concession, Sako et al v. L 705 ( IL), September 23, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Smith, Dudley and Jennings v. Auto Convoy Inc., IBT Local 327 et. al., 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Smith, Dudley et al, v. Auto Convoy Co. & Local 327 IBT, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - New York State Teamsters Council Health Fund v. Stein Roe et al; (#87-Civ-718); Countryman v. Shearson Lehman et al (#87 C 3861) Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)